Privacy Policy
==============

Effective date: **September 1st, 2021**
---------------------------------------

We care about your privacy. This page explains actions and policies in use for the information that you provide when using this website and communicate with us as a service user.

In short
--------

Exoscale only collects information you choose to give us, and processes it with your consent or on legal basis. We collect as little personal information as we can to allow us to provide our services. Personal information is not sold to third parties and is used and processed as described on this page.

We comply with the EU’s Privacy Shield framework and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We provide the same level of privacy protection regardless of your country of origin or location.

Information collected by Exoscale
---------------------------------

### Information from website browsers

If you’re browsing Exoscale websites, we rely on cookies, server logs and web analytics providers to automatically collect basic information about the visitor.

This information includes the browser type, operating system, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each request. We also collect potentially personally-identifying information such as IP addresses.

### Information from users with Exoscale accounts

On account creation, we ask for the following information:

* Email address
* Password
* Full name and/or company name
* Billing address

We also collect personal information from you when you subscribe to our newsletters. If you contact us from our website’s contact form or our support platform, we keep a copy of your communications with us. We also keep a copy of all communication we send you that is related to the providing of our services.

Use of collected information
----------------------------

We use the personal information we collect from you for the following purposes:

* To deal with your requests
* To provide you with information and access to resources that you have requested from us
* To provide you with technical support
* To improve our website’s performance and efficiency in assisting you with the use of our products
* For intrusion and misuse detection and securing access to our systems as well as enforcing our Terms of Service
* To improve our efficiency with customer service, content and functionality of our offering, to better understand our users’ needs and for general business management.
* To send important email notifications related to your use of the service.
* When you have allowed us to do so, to send occasional newsletter and marketing campaigns about our services. You can unsubscribe from these at any time using the link provided in the message.

Protection of information
-------------------------

Safe handling of your personal information when it’s entered, submitted or accessed is ensured by the use of TLS for all communications over the network.

Furthermore, we rely on PCI-compliant payment providers and do not store financial or credit card information on our servers. Identification of your account between Exoscale and the credit card processor is done through an anonymized token that we exchange in an encrypted way.

Our data isn’t encrypted at-rest, however we control access to our datacenter locations with physical and network security.

Cookies and tracking
--------------------

We use cookies and affiliated technologies such as `localStorage` to keep you logged in on our web properties and remembering your preferences.

Our web analytics provider(s) also use cookies as a tracking mechanism. We only enable analytics on our public properties and within our customer on-boarding process to improve our performance in these areas.

You can change your preferences here Cookie Settings.

Data processors
---------------

Exoscale may rely on third-party sub-processor(s) to carry out specific processing activities on behalf of the Client throughout its providing of the Services. A list of sub-processors per Service is available in the following tables:

### Compute, Storage, SKS

| Name of data processor | Purpose | Location |
| --- | --- | --- |
| (currently no third-party processor) |     |     |

### DBaaS flavors

| Name of data processor | Purpose | Location |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Aiven Oy | Orchestration of data infrastructure services instances running on Exoscale Compute | HELSINKI, Finland |

Third-party providers
---------------------

Exoscale relies on third-party providers to fulfill its operations. Exoscale hence forwards data about its Clients to these providers. Under no circumstances is data uploaded by Clients to Exoscale Services transferred to these providers.

| Name of provider | Purpose | Location |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Bexio | Accounting | Switzerland |
| Postfinance | Payment Service Provider (Legacy) | Switzerland |
| Adyen | Payment Service Provider | Netherlands |
| PayPal | Payment Service Provider | United States |
| Six (previously Aduno) | Credit card processor | Switzerland |
| Mailchimp | Newsletters and marketing campaigns | United States |
| A1 Digital International | Business intelligence | Austria |
| Amazon Web Services | Data archival | United States |
| Joincube (aka. Beamer) | Changelog user notifications | United States |
| MoocIt | Online learning platform | France |
| Kiflo | Partner registration portal | France |
| Peoplefone | VoIP telephony services | Switzerland |

Age limitations
---------------

To the extent prohibited by applicable law, we do not allow use of our Services by anyone younger than 16 years old. Exoscale does not collect information about users’ age, but if we learn that anyone younger than 16 has unlawfully provided us with personal data, we will take steps to delete such information.

Exercise of rights
------------------

As an Exoscale Client, you are entitled to exercising the following rights with regard to the personal data Exoscale holds about you:

* Right of information
* Right of access
* Right to rectification
* Right to erasure
* Right to restriction of processing
* Right to data portability
* Right to object to processing
* Right to not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing.

### Data controller contact and Data Protection Officer

Data subjects can exercise their rights by sending an email to [privacy@exoscale.com](mailto:privacy@exoscale.com). All enquiries will be handled by the Exoscale team under supervision of the Exoscale Data Privacy Officer. In accordance with Article 27 of the GDPR for controllers or processors based outside the European Union, Exoscale has appointed A1 Digital International GmbH, a company duly established and existing under the laws of Austria with its registered office at Lassallestrasse 9, 1020 Vienna, Austria as its Representative in the European Union. A1 Digital International GmbH can reached by post by sending a letter to “FAO Data Protection Officer” to the above address, or by email to [privacy@a1.digital](mailto:privacy@a1.digital).

### Data Protection Authority

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area and believe we maintain your Personal Data within the scope of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you may direct questions or complaints to our lead supervisory authority:

    Commission Nationale de l'Informatique et des Libertés
    3 Place de Fontenoy
    TSA 80715
    75334 PARIS CEDEX 07
    France

Changes to this Privacy Policy
------------------------------

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Laws, regulations and industry standards evolve, which may make those changes necessary, or we may make changes to our Services or business. We will post the changes to this page and encourage you to review our Privacy Policy to stay informed. If we make changes that materially alter your privacy rights, we will provide additional notice, such as via email or through the Services. If you disagree with the changes to this Privacy Policy, you should terminate your Exoscale account.
